《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
如果你回到卡布里卡  把箭给我带回来
If you go back to Caprica and bring me the arrow,
我会为大家指明到达地球的道路
that will show us the way to Earth.
你想让我怎样  西洛  她是赛昂人
What do you want from me, Helo? She's a Cylon.
我不会让你杀了她
I'm not gonna let you kill her!
知道吗  她怀了我的孩子
Okay? She's carrying my child!
那贱人偷了我的战机
Bitch took my ride.
我要逮捕你  总统女士
TIGH: I am placing you under arrest, Madam President.
这是兵变  你是知道的
This is mutiny. You know that.
你要递出辞呈了
ADAMA: I'm terminating your presidency, as of this moment.
我建议我们跳跃到应急备用坐标
I recommend we execute jump to emergency standby coordinates.
我们在科波上的人怎么办
What about our people on the surface of Kobol?
如果他们还活着就要等等了
If they're still alive, they'll have to wait.
他挺不住了
He's not gonna make it.
托特  你忘了医药箱  所以就要你去拿回来
Tarn, you forgot the med kit, so you're gonna have to go back and get it.
你不能让他单独去
You can't send him alone.
你在质疑我的命令吗  上士
You questioning my orders, Chief?
我不想指挥  我以前也没想过
TIGH: I don't want a command. I never did.
你现在可别在我面前就这么走了
Don't you dare die on me now.
赛昂人在攻击我们的网络
The Cylons are hacking our network.
试图登陆我们的主机
Attempting to access our mainframe.
那是什么东西
HOTDOG: What is that thing?
不知道  可不管是什么  它都在向卡拉狄加袭来
APOLLO: I don't know, but whatever it is, it's bearing on Galactica.
我们要把它干掉
We've got to take it out!
注意 抢修组速去12号甲板
WOMAN ON PA: Attention, Damage Control Team to Deck 12.
喂 喂
Hey. Hey.
注意 抢修组速去12号甲板
Attention, Damage Control Team to Deck 12.
难熬的一天  是吧?  恩
Quite a day, huh? Yeah.
有好久没看到你了
Wow, I haven't seen you in person since...
有两周了
Two weeks ago.
挺想你的
I've really been thinking about you.
谢谢  我得走了
That's nice. I gotta go.
小杜
Hey, Dee.
Dee, hey. Hey.
听我说
Listen,
我知道我还没尽力
I know that I haven't really made an effort, or it must seem
或是看起来我还没尽力…
like I really haven't made an effort
来把这...无论这是什么 当作优先考虑对象
to make this, whatever this is, a priority.
但…  但?
But... But?
但你忙于协助总统在我船上发动一场兵变?
But you were too busy helping the President spark a mutiny on my ship.
或是在你饥渴 想要勾引我之前
Or, but you wanted to wait until you were desperate
需要一个可以依靠的肩膀
and needed a shoulder to cry on before making your move?
那只是有些身不由己
I think that was a little uncalled for.
恩  抱歉  你说的对
Yeah, I'm sorry. You're right.
我得走了
I gotta go.
怎么回事?
What the hell?
去找备用手电筒
ISHAY: Grab the emergency flashlights.
好的
KIM: Copy that.
检查通风口
Check the ventilator.
存贮器访问中断
KELLY: We have DMA interrupted.
报告情况?
Report status.
正在检查
I'm checking.
检查一下子系统
GAETA: Let's check subsystems!
启动备用电源
Let's get emergency power back on!
弗莱波
HOTDOG: Flyboy!
热狗
FLYBOY: Hotdog!
我是副长  军情报告?
XO, sitrep?
是病毒  长官
It's the virus, sir.
一定是在其他计算机系统里自我生成的拷贝
I think it must have spawned copies of itself in some of the computer systems.
已破坏了主电源和辅助设备
It's knocked out main power and auxiliary units.
备用电源刚启动
GAETA: Emergency power just kicked back in.
上尉  干的好
Hey, Captain, nice work out there!
真不知道你们为什么还在欢呼喝彩
I'm not sure what you guys are kissing and hugging about.
我们弄砸了
We screwed up.
有一个漏网之鱼
We let one through.
这灯是怎么回事?
KAT: What's going on with the lights?
不太清楚
APOLLO: I'm not sure.
我们还不清楚是否可以联络到全体舰队
We still have no idea if we can reach most of the ship.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
不清楚  长官  正在检查
I'm not sure, sir. Checking.
停电了  长官  我看是全船停电
Power's out, sir. I think it's ship-wide.
只有声能电话还好用
Sound-powered phones is the only thing working.
尝试联络检修组  可线路有干扰
Been trying to get to Damage Control, but the lines are jammed.
好  安置好战机  注意武器安全
Okay. Get the birds tied down and make the ordnance safe.
我去作战信息中心 看一下到底出了什么事
I'll head up to Combat and see what the hell's going on.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
重复一次
Say again.
苏伦报告说在右舷飞行吊舱...
Cylons reported in the starboard flight pod.
有敌人入侵母舰
We've been boarded.
好  菜鸟们  走了
APOLLO: Okay, nuggets. Keep moving.
当我在他尾部出现的时候
Yeah, but when I came up on his six, all right,
他上仰了  我不得不逃跑
he rotated, so I had to bug out.
干净利索  犹如行云流水
It was plain, clean, simple.
你们看到我怎么对付 在我左舷追我的那一对了吗?
KAT: Hey, did you see when I turned on that pair chasing me on the port beam?
恩  看到了  不错
Yeah. I saw that. That was sweet.
我上仰  回撤  加速 然后就砰的一声
I rotate, pull back, hit the brakes, and there, bang!
左侧的那个排成了死区上限
Left one's lined up dead-center ring.
我紧接着干掉了他 回首又干掉了他的僚机--
I chatter him, turn back to get his wingman...
天啊
Jesus!
是赛昂人!快!快跑!
APOLLO: Cylons! Come on! Move!
干!离开这里!
Come on! Let's get out of here!
快走!快!快!
Come on! Come on! Go! Go!
天啊  它来了
My gods! It's coming!
快跑!
KAT: Go! Go! Go!
离开这  快
APOLLO: Get the hell out! KAT: Go!
起来 快跑
Get up! Get out! Go now, now!
操!
Frak!
没事吧  上尉?
You all right, Captain?
还有一口气儿  我看没事
I'm still breathing. I guess that's all right.
小凯
Kat!
热狗  你们没事吧?
Hotdog, you all right?
没事
HOTDOG: Think so.
我先看看再说
Can I get back to you on that?
军情报告?
Sitrep?
有敌人入侵母舰  长官
We've been boarded, sir.
不清楚人数  所在地和走向
We don't know how many, where they are, where they're headed.
普通武器对它们根本毫发无伤
Our standard ammo doesn't even make a dent.
只有榴弹才能干掉它们
The explosive rounds are the only way to take them down.
你那还有多少?
How many rounds you got?
刚才那是最后一颗了
That was our last one.
好吧
All right.
热狗
Hotdog?
把这个带去作战信息中心
Take this to CIC.
给泰上校或当值军官
Give it to Colonel Tigh or the officer in charge.
是  长官
HOTDOG: Yes, sir.
陆战队的兄弟们  咱们去打赛鬼子
Marines, let's go toaster shopping.
一切安全  长官
All clear, sir.
小凯跟着我
Kat, on me.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
各船注意
GAETA: Galactica to all ships:
赛昂突击队已经侵入我船
We have been boarded by a Cylon raiding party.
禁止接近或试图在卡拉狄加内停泊
Do not approach or attempt to dock with Galactica.
在确认母舰安全之前请保持安全距离
Keep a safe distance until we have secured the ship.
重复 赛昂突击队已经侵入我…
I say again, we have been boarded by a Cylon raiding...
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
赛昂人干扰了信号
The Cylons jammed the signal.
好嘛
Great.
是枪声吗?
Are those gunshots?
恩
Yeah.
我们不能留在这里
We can't stay in here.
打开门
ROSLIN: Open the door.
你知道我不可以这么做  总统女士
You know I can't do that, Madam President.
温纳下士  我可不想被锁在这里
Corporal Venner, I have no intention of being locked in this cell
任人宰割  把门打开!
and shot like a rat in a cage. Open the door!
多谢
Thank you.
喂  喂
Hey! Hey! Hey!
温纳下士  别开枪!
APOLLO: Corporal Venner, don't shoot!
我是阿达玛上尉  我带着一个火力小组
It's Captain Adama! I have a fire team with me!
进来  上尉
Come on in, Captain.
看守升降扶梯
APOLLO: Watch the companionway.
安全  长官
We're clear, sir.
有敌人入侵母舰
We've been boarded.
甲板上都是赛昂人
This deck is crawling with Cylons.
它们企图到达军火库
They're trying to get to the magazines.
我们能帮什么忙?
How can we help?
活下来  别中枪
Stay alive and don't get shot.
把赛昂人交给我们
Leave the Cylons to us.
好  医务室是安全地点
Okay, sickbay is the safest spot.
那里离任何潜在目标都是最远的
It's farthest away from any potential targets,
同时被设计成避难所以防母舰失守
and it's designed to function as a disaster shelter in case the ship were lost.
对
Right.
伯宁顿  备用武器
Bonnington, sidearm.
长官
Sir.
好的  比利
Okay, Billy.
以前用过枪吗?
You ever handled a weapon before?
10岁的时候用过我舅舅的废皮枪
A pellet gun from my uncle when I was, like, 10.
原理是一样的  真枪只不过声音大点
The principle's the same, the real ones just make a bigger noise.
总统女士
Madam President.
不  谢谢你  我使不了
No, thank you. I can't.
下士  是  长官
Corporal. Yes, sir.
你负责送她到医务室
You're in charge of getting her down to sickbay.
伯宁顿和你一起护送
Take Bonnington as escort.
记住  远离枪声
Remember, just head away from the sound of gunfire.
好
All right.
那你呢?
What about you?
我们要向着有枪声的地方去
Well, we're heading towards the gunfire.
好  听好了
Okay, listen up.
两层以下  在亡命徒堤道有一个轻型武器库
There's a small arms locker on causeway Bravo, two decks down.
我们去那里取些榴弹
We're gonna go get some explosive rounds
然后直奔军火库
and then we're heading towards the magazines.
特纳姆?  长官
Twinam? TWINAM: Sir.
你作先头  是  长官
You take point. TWINAM: Yes, sir.
祝你们好运  上尉
Good luck, Captain.
愿主保佑你们
May the lords protect you.
恩  也保佑您
And you, too.
安全  好  我们走
TWINAM: Clear. APOLLO: Okay, let's go!
快走
Move.
我们该出城去
HELO: We should probably head out of the city,
侦察一下偏远的空军基地
try to scout one of the outlying air bases,
看是否能找到一架猛禽
see if we can find a Raptor.
我可真没想到
It's not exactly what I expected.
还以为会在街道上踩到腐尸
I thought I'd be stepping over decaying corpses in the streets.
恩  我们零零散散地看到了一些尸体
Yeah, we saw a few bodies here and there.
不是很多  莎伦说…
Not much though. Sharon said...
赛昂人莎伦说他们派过军队清理尸体
Cylon Sharon said they had troops picking up the bodies,
然后投到集中焚化炉中
transporting them to mass incinerators.
你女友身世显贵
STARBUCK: Your girlfriend's from a lovely family.
家人和善 很好的价值观
Good people, great values.
够了  好吗?
Enough, all right?
好  我被她耍了
Okay, I was fooled by her. She fooled me.
你高兴了?
You happy now?
这不是我高不高兴的事
It's not about making me happy.
那是什么?
Then what's it about?
你想怎样? 你想让我说我是他妈的白痴? 好
What do you want here? You want me to say I'm a frakking idiot? Okay.
我他妈是个白痴
I'm a frakking idiot.
这样你会好受些了?
That make you feel better?
我管不了那么多了  我都在这呆了几个月了
I don't care anymore. I've been here for months, by myself,
独自逃亡  赛昂人在后面紧追不舍
on the run, one step ahead of the Cylons.
事实上一直和赛昂人在一起
With the Cylons, I guess, actually.
她看起来如此真实
She seemed so real.
像莎伦一样  你知道吗
Like Sharon, you know?
一样的咧嘴一笑  一样的微笑  一切细节都一样
Same grin, same laugh, all the little things.
我爱上了一个机器
I fell in love with a machine.
好傻啊  所以叫我白痴吧 这件事我们到此为止吧
It's stupid, so just call me an idiot, and let's be done with it.
你个白痴  知道吗?你是白痴
You're an idiot. All right? You're an idiot.
可赛昂人自有办法把我们弄得都和白痴一样
But the Cylons have a way of making all of us look like idiots.
卡拉  干什么去?
Kara, what are you doing?
中途站
Making a pit stop.
我要拿些东西
I've got something I gotta pick up.
我们得继续走
Hey, we gotta keep going.
这是我的住所  西洛
I got a place here, Helo.
赛昂人的病毒 在我们断开网络连接之前
GAETA: The Cylon virus spawned itself in our subsystems
在我们的子系统中自我繁殖了
before we broke the network.
我已派人清理各子系统
I had teams cleaning each subsystem,
但恢复主电力至少还要一小时
but it'll be at least an hour before we restore main power.
上尉?  手头上所有的陆战队员…
Captain? What few Marines we have
都已在检查点集结完毕 但通讯受干扰
are assembling at their checkpoint, but comm. is spotty.
赛昂人在哪里?
Where are the Cylons?
看来它们分成了两队
It looks like they split into two forces.
一队向前...
One moving forward...
另一队向舰尾进发了
Forward, one moving aft.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我见过这样的事  这是它们的目标
I've seen this before. These are their objectives.
第二检修组以及辅助消防组  长官
Secondary Damage Control and Auxiliary Fire Control, sir.
如果它们成功了  就会使减压安全装置过载
If they're successful, they will override our decompression safeties
把我们喷到太空里去
and vent us all into space.
一旦我们死了 它们就会调转炮口
Once we're all dead, they'll turn the ship's guns
扫平整个舰队
on the fleet and wipe it out once and for all.
波塔尔博士
Dr. Baltar.
老天  您到底是怎么找到我们的?
How, in God's name, did you find us?
怀里抱的是什么?
What do you have there?
很明显是个婴儿
It's a child, obviously.
婴儿
A child?
我能抱一下吗?
Can I hold it?
请...
Please.
这就是即将降临的生命吗?
Is this the shape of things to come?
我是那么想的
That's my understanding.
那它所面对的只有一件事了
Only one thing for it, then.
指挥官
Commander?
拜托  指挥官  您要去哪儿?
Please! Commander, where are you going?
回来!
Come back!
指挥官!
Commander!
Commander! Commander.
指挥官!  拜托
Commander, please.
不!
No!
他杀了我们的孩子
He killed our baby.
我们的孩子?
Our baby?
阿达玛  我看到他把孩子淹死了
Adama, I saw him drown the baby.
为什么有人要把孩子淹死呢?
Why would anyone want to drown a baby?
盖尤斯  答案就在我们的左右
Gaius, the answer is all around us.
这里出了什么事?
What happened here?
人祭
Human sacrifice.
并非是你的"经文"中让你相信的那些神话
Not the fairytales your scriptures would have you believe.
我本以为科波会是一个天堂或是什么
I thought Kobol was supposed to be a paradise, or something.
诸神与人类...
Some place where
共存的地方
gods lived with the humans in harmony, or...
也许只是一时而已  然后你们的本性就影响了这里
For a time, perhaps. Then your true nature asserted itself.
你们的残暴  堕落  野蛮
Your brutality. Your depravity. Your barbarism.
那"经文"上所说的全是谎言了?
So the scriptures are all a lie.
只是谎言  都是为这些野蛮行为而做的幌子
It's all just a lie, just a cover-up for all this savagery.
正是如此
Exactly.
这一切在之前都发生过   盖尤斯
All of this has happened before, Gaius,
这一切都将再次重演
and all of it will happen again.
阿达玛
Adama.
人类本性终究会对这一切产生影响
Mankind's true nature will always assert itself.
那他会杀了我们的孩子
So he will try and kill our baby.
除非你坐视不管  盖尤斯
Only if you let him, Gaius.
除非你让他那么干
Only if you let him.
眼睛看前方  快!
Keep your eyes up ahead. Come on.
快!  走  走  走
Come on. Go! Go! Go! Go!
安全了吗?  恩
Is it clear? TWINAM: Yeah.
安全了吗?  所有甲板安全 长官
Is it clear? TWINAM: All decks, sir.
键盘失效了
APOLLO: The keypad's dead.
好...别开枪 别开枪  我是人类!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! I'm human!
吉默尔
KAT: Jammer?
是  长官  是我  是我 吉默尔
Yes, sir, it's me. It's me, Jammer.
别开枪  是吉默尔
Jammer. Don't shoot. Please. It's Jammer.
科利肖!  长官
APOLLO: Collishaw! COLLISHAW: Sir!
把守舱门
Watch the hatch!
小凯  特维纳姆  去找榴弹
Kat, Twinam, find those explosive rounds.
长官
Sir.
这里出了什么事?
What the hell happened here?
不知道  长官  我没参战
I don't know, sir. I wasn't here in this fight.
我只是躲在这里
I just came in here to hide.
到处都是赛昂人
The Cylons are everywhere.
好  冷静  冷静  你会没事的
All right, settle down. You're gonna be just fine.
阿波罗
KAT: Apollo?
开玩笑吧  就这么多了?
You're kidding me. That's it?
本来就没多少  长官
Didn't have much to begin with, sir.
一定是其他的火力小组 在我们之前把这里一扫而空
The other fire teams must've come and cleaned the locker out before us.
6颗  我们有5个人
Six rounds, there are five of us.
好  你们一人一颗
Okay, well, each of you guys take one.
剩下的我拿
I'll take the reload.
等等  你没把我算在内  是吧  长官
You're not counting me, are you, sir?
我…  我只是…
I mean, I'm just...
我只是个拖后腿的
I'm just a knuckle dragger here.
我不知道怎么和赛昂武士打仗
I don't know to fight Centurions.
对赛昂武士一点也不了解啊
I don't know the first thing about fighting Centurions.
来  我们走
Come on, let's go.
开火
HELO: Let's do it.
想找钥匙的时候就是找不到
Never have your house keys when you need them.
这出自你手?  你画的吗  卡拉?
These yours? You paint these, Kara?
恩
Yeah.
电从哪里来的?
How the hell did you get power?
电池
Batteries.
总是被断电
Kept turning off the power.
好象是因为没付电费吧
Something about not paying the bill.
这绝对不是你的风格
That is definitely not you.
家父的
It's my dad.
还有一袋方便面
Well, we've got one package of noodles.
你不喜欢买来的食物?
You don't believe in groceries?
反正我就从没喜欢过这地方
You know, I never really liked this place, anyway.
夏天空调不好用
Air conditioning doesn't work in the summer.
冬天暖气不好使
Heater doesn't work in the winter.
租金还高的惊人
The rent's a crime.
自从袭击过后  我还从没...
After the attack, I never,
从没动过我那些破烂儿
never pined over any of my old crap.
也不想它们
Never missed it.
抬眼望去就是烦的要命的停车场
The stupid view of the parking lot,
卫生间里的马桶还坏了
broken toilet in the bathroom.
我所认识的每个人都拼命去找回曾经属于自己的东西
You know, everyone I know is fighting to get back what they had.
我拼命则是因为除了打仗就不会做别的事了
I'm fighting 'cause I don't know how to do anything else.
离医务室还有多远?
ROSLIN: How far to sickbay?
60米
VENNER: Sixty meters.
她停止呼吸没多久
DUALLA: She stopped breathing a while ago.
小杜?
BILLY: Dee?
哦  天啊  是小杜
Oh, my gods, it's Dee.
你还好吧?
Hey, are you all right?
恩  我正要去舰首
Yeah. I was going to the head...
天那  你在流血
Oh, my gods, you're bleeding.
去我的搁物架
Went back to my rack.
你中枪了?
Are you shot?
我忘了些东西
I forgot something.
喂
Hey.
小杜  看着我  小杜?
Dee, look at me. Dee, look at me. Dee?
喊她军衔
Try using her rank.
杜亚拉中士  看着我
Petty Officer Dualla, look at me.
嗨
Hey.
很高兴见到你
I'm glad to see you.
我在黑暗中好一阵了
I've been here in the dark a long time.
可能是脑震荡
It's probably a concussion.
温纳下士  我们得换条路去医务室
Corporal Venner, we need an alternate route to sickbay.
睁开眼  看着我
Open your eyes. Look at me.
我们可不想去有枪声的地方
We don't want to walk into gunfire.
我们要避开赛昂人
We want to go away from the Cylons.
整理一下你的思绪  想一想
Now clear your head. Come on.
我们只能…
We can go only...
沿着右舷那侧走  但要远很多
All the way on the starboard side. It's a lot farther.
好  右舷  我们走
Good. Starboard, let's go.
华莱士中尉报告说 他的小组
Lieutenant Wallace reports his unit destroyed
在这个接合处消灭了两名赛昂武士
two Centurions at this junction.
他们把第三名围困在了母舰的洗衣间里
They've trapped a third in the ship's laundry.
那个赛昂武士已无法走动  但仍在射击
It can't walk, but it's still shooting.
至少我们把对辅助消防组的威胁遏制住了
At least we've contained the threat to Auxiliary Fire Control.
相信我  它们仍直奔舰尾检修组而去
Trust me, they're still heading for the Aft Damage Control.
盖塔中尉
Lieutenant Gaeta?
海恩中士报告说她的作战小组
Sergeant Hadrian reports her unit's had to halt their advance
不得不在10号甲板第69间停下来
on Deck 10 at frame 69.
赛昂在切割她前方的舰体
Cylons cut through the hull ahead of her
隔间已破损直通向太空了
and the compartments are open to space.
妙招  为了防止我们追赶它们
Smart move. Keeps us from chasing them.
没人阻止最后两名赛昂人…
TIGH: There's nothing between the last two Cylons
前往减压安全装置了
and the decompression safeties.
企求老天保佑吧
If you know any prayers, now's the time.
我们休息5分钟吧
What do you say we take five?
你说还有多远?
How much further do you think?
托特被杀了  不是你的错
Tarn getting shot, it wasn't your fault.
这你是知道的  是吧?
You know that, right?
上士
Chief?
说话啊  混蛋!
Talk to me, you motherfrakker!
混蛋?
Motherfrakker.
瑟纳塞斯最好知道珍惜这一切
Socinus better appreciate this.
他十有八九像个帝王似的沐浴在阳光中呢
He's probably lying in the sun like some godsdamn emperor.
他是个傻蛋
He's an idiot.
但愿他没事
I hope he's okay.
他会没事的  那小子命硬着呢
He'll be fine. He's a tough kid.
我们给他拿去医药箱就可以了  好
We just gotta get him the med kit. Yeah.
该走了  凯莉
We gotta go, Cally.
你到底去哪儿了? 去哪儿了?
Where the hell have you been? Where have you been?
博士  去哪儿了?说话啊
I... Doc, where have you been? Answer me.
我迷路了…说话啊
I got lost in the... Answer me!
博士  不要到处乱跑  好吗
Doc, you never run off like that, all right?
你听我指挥
You're under my command.
这是军事行动  明白吗?
This is military operations, you understand me?
我想听你说的是"是  长官!"
What I want to hear from you is, "Yes, sir!"
是  长官
Yes, sir.
听我说  克莱斯当
Look, Crashdown, I...
我对这地方有种不详的预感
I'm getting a really bad feeling about this place...
恩  我们都一样
Yeah, you and me both, Doc.
闪光  "闪光"
TYROL: Flash. Flash!
雷声
Thunder.
走  走
TYROL: Go, go.
这边
Here.
托特呢?
Where's Tarn?
出了什么事?
What happened?
赛昂人
The Cylons.
被跟踪了吗?  没有
Were you followed? No.
他怎么样了?
How's he doing?
他不行了
He's not gonna make it.
什么?
TYROL: What?
什么意思?  你在说什么?
What do you mean? What are you talking about?
我们拿来了医药箱  给他打一针
We got the med kit. Give him a shot!
再给他打一针!
Give him another shot!
太晚了
It's too late.
太晚了是什么意思?
What do you mean it's too late?
我给你拿来了医药箱
TYROL: I got you the med kit.
你还要什么?
What else do you want?
我们拿来了你需要的药
So we go get the medicine you asked for.
托特…  为了什么啊?
Tarn... For what?
就为这一切吗!
For this.
拜托  你怎么也得做点事
Come on, you gotta do something.
做点事
You have to do something.
我无力回天  上士
I can't change that he's gonna die, Chief.
这个过程会漫长且痛苦 我们可以让他免受这些苦
It's going to be slow and painful, and we can spare him that.
我们可以让他免受这些痛苦 只要给他我的箱子…
We can spare him that if we give him the morpha from my kit
和你那箱子里的吗啡
and the one that you brought back.
什么?
What?
不
No.
中尉
El-tee?
中尉  说说话啊
El-tee, come on.
他是你的人  上士
He's your man, Chief.
给我  给我
Give it to me. Give it to me.
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
我是上士  感觉怎么样?
It's Chief. How you doing?
怎么回事  上士?
What's going on, Chief?
你知道…  你就听鸟叫吧
Well, you know, listening to the birds.
我拿些东西为你止痛
I got a little something for the pain.
有好消息  兄弟  救援队来了
Good news, buddy. We got a rescue party here.
猛禽号刚降落
Raptor just landed.
我们会把你送上去 然后送你回卡拉狄加  好吗?
We're gonna put you on it and take you back to Galactica. Okay?
我要回母舰了?
We're going home?
恩  要回母舰了
Yeah. We're going home.
进展的怎么样了  吉默尔?
How're you coming, Jammer?
应该可以了  上尉
That should do it, Captain.
干的好  你们检查甲板  检查储物柜
Hey, nice job. You guys, check the deck, check the lockers.
这里应该还有榴弹
There's gotta be more rounds in here.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
作战信息中心  12-8-6-4-2 轻武库
Combat, 12-8642, Arms Locker.
我是阿波罗
Apollo here.
上校  是阿波罗
Colonel, it's Apollo.
他在12号甲板  舰尾间8-6
He's on Deck 12, aft frame 86, between
在赛昂人与舰尾检修组之间
the Cylons and Aft Damage Control.
阿波罗  我是副长  军情报告
Apollo, XO, sitrep.
5颗榴弹
Five armed effectives.
在这里到机库之间
We haven't seen anything but bodies
除了尸体还没发现任何情况
between here and the hangar deck.
安全
BONNINGTON: Clear.
好  按我的记忆
Okay, from what I can remember,
过了那舱门20米远就到医务室了
the sickbay is about 20 meters through that hatch.
感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
像是在水中走路一样
Like I'm walking underwater.
有陆战队员和你们在一起吗
Any Marines with you?
科利肖和特维纳姆大兵
Privates Collishaw, Twinam.
带上你的人直奔舰尾检修组
Take your men and proceed without delay to Aft Damage Control.
那东西是你的?
Is that yours?
恩  我想现在归我了吧
Yeah, I guess it is now.
好  你要是想那样放在裤子里
Okay. If you're gonna keep it in your trousers like that,
最好还是把保险打开
you might want to turn the safety on.
好的
Great.
卡住了?
VENNER: Is it stuck?
干!  舱门打不开
No, frak! The hatch won't open.
另一侧被减压了
The other side's been depressurized.
好吧  温纳下士 这是你的船
All right, Corporal Venner, this is your ship.
我们只是游客
I'm just a tourist.
再找一条去医务室的路吧
Find us another way to sickbay.
好
Okay.
好  我们得直奔舰尾检修组去了
Okay, we have to head toward Aft Damage Control.
舰尾检修组
Aft Damage Control.
舰尾检修组?
APOLLO: Aft Damage Control?
那就是它们的目标
That's what they're after.
不要再浪费时间了
Let's not waste any more time.
快去舰尾检修组
You get to Aft Damage Control.
现在他妈的立刻赶去那里  先生
And get there right frakking now, mister.
在赛昂人之前赶去那里 不然我们的船就失守了  明白了吗?
Get there before the Cylons or we lose the ship. Is that clear?
立即赶往检修组  这就去 阿波罗结束通话
Aft Damage Control. RFN. On our way. Apollo out.
好了  等下
Okay. Hold on.
好  安全
Okay, we made it.
特维纳姆  吉默尔  你们守这边
Twinam, Jammer, you take this side.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
小凯  科利肖  你们守那边
APOLLO: Kat, Collishaw, you take that side.
我们要找些掩体
We're gonna need some cover.
好了 行动
All right, let's move.
把这东西弄出去
Let's get this stuff out.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
等下
Wait.
不错
That's not so...
好  各位  爬下  蹲下
Okay, everybody, get down. Stay down.
在我给出信号前不准开火
Hold your fire till I give the signal.
记住  你们每人只有一颗榴弹
Remember, you only have one round,
所以一定要爆头才能干掉它们
so it's gotta be a headshot to make a kill.
明白了吗?  明白了吗?
You understand? Understood?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
小凯  关掉手电
Kat, kill the flashlight.
找掩体!
Take cover. Take cover.
走  快走!
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
挺住  吉默尔
APOLLO: Steady up there, Jammer.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
还真不习惯这样  长官
Not really cut out for this, sir.
我也是
Me, neither.
有时候不得不孤注一掷
But sometimes you gotta roll the hard six.
什么意思  长官?
What does that mean, sir?
不知道  我老爸说过这句话
I don't know. It's something my dad says.
没有我的命令不要开火就是了
Just don't shoot till I tell you to, all right?
好了  我们阵势不错  它们快来了
Okay, we're in good shape. They're coming.
我们阵形好
But we're in good shape.
爆头  装弹  爆头
Headshot. Reload. Headshot.
装弹  爆头
Reload. Headshot.
它们来了  大家蹲下
Okay, they're coming. Everybody down!
如果想开枪就要关保险
You want to shoot that, you have to take the safety off.
开火!
Fire!
干!
Hey.
您没事吧?
Are you all right?
是的  我很好
Yes, I'm fine.
我们成功了!把它们都消灭了!
We did it. We got them all!
它们现在可没那么高大了  是吧?
They don't look so big now, do they?
它们可够高大的了
They look big enough.
哦  天哪
KAT: Oh, gods.
还是我拿着吧
DUALLA: I'll take that.
好
Yeah.
您受伤了吗?
VENNER: Have you been shot?
没有  我看没有
No, I don't think so.
恩?
Yeah?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
哦！
Oh!
诸神一定是在保佑您
The gods must be watching over you.
不想走了?
Tired of walking?
好
Okay.
谢了
Thanks.
嗨
Hey.
感觉怎么样?
How you feel?
好些了
Better.
你不是说过…
I thought you said...
别去想我以前说过什么
Forget what I said
听我现在说什么
and listen to what I'm saying.
你在听吗?
Are you listening?
呃…
Uh-huh.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry.
我没听见  你能...
I didn't hear that. Could you...
能再来一次吗?
Could you do that one more time?
来  听个清清楚楚吧
Come here. Let me be clear.
帘子拉上
Get the curtain.
卡托医生正赶来
TIGH: Doc Cottle's on his way.
随时可能到
He'll be here any minute.
他会没事的  这你知道
He's gonna be all right. You know that.
恩  恩  我知道
Yeah. Yeah, I know that.
上校  我看我的牢房还在等我吧
Colonel, I assume there's still a cell out there waiting for me?
没错
That's right.
温纳下士  我准备好了
Corporal Venner, I'm ready.
真不敢相信你居然和那个女人一边来反抗老头子
I can't believe you sided with that woman against the old man.
如果不是你用枪指着我的头 我也就不会这么做了
I wouldn't do that if you put a gun to my head, and you did.
可你既然做了  我想你也就不配穿这身军装
As far as I'm concerned, you're not fit to wear a uniform.
这你倒说对了
You're right about that part.
我不配穿这身军装
I am not fit to wear the uniform.
也许从来都不配
And maybe I never was.
可你也不配
Then again, neither were you.
但这不是我的战舰  我敢肯定也不是你的  而是他的
But this isn't my ship, and it sure as hell isn't yours. It's his.
当他醒来后  他会来决定如何发落我们
And when he wakes up, he'll decide what to do with the both of us.
谢天谢地  我幸亏没孩子
Thank the gods I didn't have kids.